# **HUNTER GROFF**

Available July 2024

huntergroff22@gmail.com I 802-598-8758 I Boston, MA huntergroff.com I linkedin.com/in/hunter-groff I github.com/huntergroff

# **SUMMARY**

Versatile and hard-working Software Engineer, recently graduated with highest honors and over a year of professional experience. Knowledgeable in both frontend and backend systems, with a specialization in modern web application frameworks including Javascript, React, and Node. Comfortable programming in Python, Java, and other object-oriented languages. Recent academic experience training and analyzing Al models using Python, Pandas, Numpy, and Matplotlib.

# **EDUCATION**

Northeastern University, Boston, MA I Khoury College of Computer Sciences

Sept. 2019 - May 2024

B.S. Computer Science and Design

GPA: 3.98 / 4.0, Summa Cum Laude

Honors: Northeastern Merit Scholarship, Yazijian Memorial Scholarship

**Activities:** Kinematix Dance Troupe (Executive Board Member)

Relevant Coursework: Object-Oriented Design, Fundamentals of Software Engineering, Algorithms and Data,

Discrete Structures, Programming Basics, Web Development, Artificial Intelligence

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

Languages: Java, Python, Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS, SQL, Swift, Objective-C

**Design Tools:** AutoCAD, Sketchup, Figma, SwiftUI, XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere, InDesign

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### iOS Engineering Co-op I Notability, San Francisco, CA

Jan. 2023 - July 2023

- Owned and managed the code for the note page management user interface. Implemented new designs from Figma files, created and assigned tickets, improved functionality, and authorized changes for this area of the app.
- Converted 10 files from Objective-C and UIKit to Swift and SwiftUI, contributing to efforts to modernize the codebase.
- Replaced local variables and functions with observed redux values as part of company-wide shift to redux framework.

#### Web Developer I Synergy Center for Dance, Jericho, VT

July 2022 - Sept. 2022

- Designed and developed a dance studio website as a single-page React app with mobile-responsive CSS.
- Integrated EmailJS, Google Sheets, and Jackrabbit class scheduling APIs using Javascript and RESTful practices.
- Collaborated with the studio owner to host and regularly update the website using lonos framework.

#### Software Engineering Co-op I CarGurus, Boston, MA

Jan. 2022 - July 2022

- Decomposed the multivariate testing framework from the monolith to develop it into an independent web service.
- Assembled a team to upgrade the image processor and test loading various image formats, improving company's SEO.
- · Developed a Python script to validate millions of converted images and deployed on AWS lambda.
- · Created database tables in SQL with Java entities and delivered data to FTL webpages using Apache Struts framework.

# **PROJECTS**

# DataAnnotation Al Training I Python, Pandas, Excel, Javascript

April 2024 - Present

- · Testing and bug-fixing Al generated code in Python and Javascript to parse data, communicate with APIs, and more.
- · Writing and analyzing prompts to train AI models to deliver more accurate and effective responses.

# Al "Ultimate Tic Tac Toe" Opponent I Python, Al Gymnasium, Numpy

Feb. 2024 - Apr. 2024

- Implemented an AI agent to play "Ultimate Tic Tac Toe," a game with approximately 1050 possible arrangements.
- · Designed a minimax algorithm to determine the best possible move, and improved said algorithm via hill-climbing.
- · Utilized multiprocessing, alpha-beta pruning, and numpy operations to increase efficiency of algorithm iteration process.

# Wishlist Web App I React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, Tailwind CSS

Oct. 2023 - Dec. 2023

- · Designed and developed a web application where users could create and share wishlists and follow other users.
- Connected a MongoDB with 5 schemas to a React.js web app with Node.js, Express.js, and RESTful practices.
- Integrated Target RedCircle API to fetch and cache data and products from Target.com for use in user-created wishlists.

# Personal Portfolio Website I React.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, React Hooks

July 2022 - Sept. 2022

- Designed and implemented a React web-app portfolio to host graphic design work and coding projects.
- Utilized React hooks to create a "light mode dark mode" toggle for the website UI.